[Music]
blessings everyone this is Chris Kendall
from the rod Vantage comm registered
Holistic Nutritionist raw food lifestyle
coach and rush chef today I'm excited to
share with you one of my favorite
recipes of all time
cocoa butter veggies 2.0 otherwise known
as Chris's creamy curry
[Music]
alright guys so I'm super excited to
share this recipe with you if you've
been following me for a while you know
I've been a raw foodist for over 15
years and putting this all out there on
the rod vanish calm for 10 and for nine
of those years I've been teasing you
with cocoa butter mint teas all admit
has been one of my long-term favorite
cravings Buster's recipes and by
cravings Buster's what I mean is it's a
recipe that when you just feel like you
need something a little bit extra or you
want to serve with other people that
really aren't into raw food maybe or
veganism they will love it just as much
and you feel really say and enjoy
it and I've had this must be free for
years and I've been putting pictures out
and sharing it and recently I've
upgraded this is now the 2.0 and the
reason they're being is the original one
which is in tra a retreat treats you
know delicious raw vegan treats can find
that over here I upgraded it because it
originally used coconut milk which one
can be a little bit harder to find and
expensive you know using a whole brown
coconut sometimes they go bad plus the
fatty acid profile for that isn't super
favorable to have all the time super
high in saturated fat and lately you
know the last year I've been in the
mastering raw food nutrition course at
dr. rick and karen dina some of the most
unbiased well scientifically rounded raw
food nutrition courses that I've ever
seen out there and they really go into
the importance of a high omega-3 or a
balanced omega-3 to 6 fatty acid ratio
in your diet for optimal health for a
variety of reasons like inflammation and
brain health the conversion of those
Omega threes into DHA a whole bunch of
other factor ism and because of that and
because I love this recipe so much I
decided to upgrade it
and taint it from the coconut milk
instead into my own seed based milk so
utilizing hemp and flax seeds which both
are nutritional powerhouses way beyond
the Omega threes amazing amino acid
profiles as well and just really damn
delicious so I wanted to let you guys
know that and again check out that
mastering raw food nutrition course it's
a full year course it's like a
college-level course I'm in it I've been
saying nutrition for over 19 years and
I'm still learning a ton and I'm sure
you can too because good education is
one of the main facets to a long healthy
raw vegan lifestyle
so let's look into this actual recipe
there's three major ingredients there's
a bulk of the curry and I'm actually
gonna give you two options for one of
them so the first one cauliflower I
absolutely love cauliflower and you know
you can actually use cauliflower totally
raw and crunchy if you like but if you
want this to taste a little bit more
authentic like a cook to Indian curry
then you'll want to use one of my
all-time favorite simple tips to make
raw vegetables taste cooked and what
that is it's freezing it so the second
ingredient which is your choice is
either cherry or grape tomatoes or fresh
peas from the pod now right now it
species and I absolutely love peas
they're super amazing they're also
higher in calories and really high in
that lysine and leucine to amino acids
that aren't super high in a lot of other
raw vegan plant foods so they make a
great addition to the diet look at those
little babies you can just take them out
of the pod and you can freeze them as
well same as the cauliflower that
softens them up makes them feel a little
bit more cooked otherwise you can use
them fresh and if you're not a hundred
percent strictly raw vegan you can use
frozen peas which truthfully I do on
occasion as well because I love them and
it tastes good I feel great beating up
number three is mushrooms I absolutely
love mushrooms
especially when I de hydrate them or put
them in the Sun which I'll get a little
bit more into mushrooms are really high
in protein there are a little bit more
dense and chewy give an awesome
different texture into your raw food
cuisine and there they're higher in
certain minerals and other
aspects that aren't really as high and
other plant foods such as chromium and
selenium so the reason I like to put
them in the Sun especially Gill side up
is because it multiplies the vitamin D
content again another nutrient that
isn't really found in many plant foods
if any really besides mushrooms when you
put them up to the Sun they can multiply
up to 400% the vitamin D also I like to
put them in the dehydrator for about an
hour and a half before serving them and
that just kind of crisps them up makes
them a little bit juicy and a little bit
more of a robust flavor you can learn a
lot more about mushrooms why I love them
and why they're one of my top four
sources of vitamin D on a raw vegan diet
and my post below all right so we're
gonna start this recipe with the
cauliflower and the peas or the tomatoes
so cauliflower break it up into small
little bits put on a baking tray or
cookie tray so you can easily freeze it
in one layer that way it freezes faster
and it's easier to separate if you're
using those fresh peas you can put them
on the same tray put it all into the
freezer and it'll be ready the next day
now in the morning you can take it out
and let it thaw or even a little bit
more of a hurry and you didn't take it
out to thaw you can just run it under
warm water in a colander and let them
thaw that way place both the peas and
the cauliflower in a large bowl if
you're not using the peas take the
cherry or grape tomatoes and cut them in
half and place them in the bowl we're
using about 1 pound 2 cauliflower or 460
grams as well as one pound of peas or
cherry or grape tomatoes for the
mushrooms you're going to use 3/4 of a
pound or 345 grams fresh chopped those
in half or into quarters and place them
in the Sun and you work from 4 to 12
hours otherwise you can just put them in
the dehydrator for an hour to 2 hours
once those are dehydrated place them in
the bowl with the other two ingredients
and mix it up now if you guys want you
can use half peas 1/2 tomatoes or one or
the other whatever you like enjoy it all
now we're going to get into the actual
curry now this is a lot of fun and it
only takes a few minutes all you have to
do is take one
quarter cup of hemp seeds and 1/8 a cup
of flax put that in your blender 1.5
tablespoons of your curry powder of
choice I like just a regular mild or
medium claw curry and then one
tablespoon of smoked paprika or
otherwise chili powder now chili powder
is different from what most people hear
chili powder here in Canada is actually
a spice mix so in the link below to the
recipe post of this I'll have a bonus
recipe for chili powder if you want to
use that instead of smoked paprika a
thumb or about 25 grams of fresh ginger
add in 2 to 3 medjool dates make sure
you've hit it the white parts are bulbs
of 3 green onions reserving the green
tops aside with one cup of pure water
blend all these ingredients until nice
and smooth in your Vitamix blender if
you don't have a Vitamix you can click
my link above and get yours for the best
price with free shipping a few optional
ingredients in case you want to make it
a little bit more rich and spicy you can
also add in 1 teaspoon of fresh turmeric
or otherwise half a teaspoon of powdered
turmeric 1/4 teaspoon of mustard seeds
1/4 teaspoon of black pepper 1/4
teaspoon of cumin and hot pepper to
taste blend until smooth now that you've
got this really thick and rich curry
paste we're gonna add point 7 5 pounds
or 345 grams of fresh juicy tomatoes
blend that until it's really nice and
smooth once that's really nice and
smooth we'll add one whole bunch or 50
grams of cilantro as well as the green
onion and just pulse blend these
ingredients until they're evenly
distributed throughout the sauce take
this beautiful aromatic delicious sauce
and pour it slowly over top of all the
chunky veggies stir it up and get ready
to enjoy now
at that this is no joke
you can definitely let it's a little bit
let those flavors marinate and kind of
settle in a good career you can use you
know 15 to 20 minutes sip before it's
totally really melded together all the
flavors just pop right out that also
gets the mushrooms a little bit more
absorbed with the sauce too this
actually keeps really well overnight and
for your information this serves one
banana commander or up to three people
you know you could serve it with a salad
just have a medium sized portion on the
side with the peas here this whole thing
is 1232 calories and 54 grams of protein
pretty amazing stuff if you sub the peas
for the tomatoes is about 980 calories
and about 35 grams of protein what do
you think guys should give it a try
hmm oh that's a big spoon let's make
sure you get everything in every bite
there we go there we go
[Laughter]
Wow well there you have it guys this is
one of my absolute all-time favorite
dinners and I just had to share with you
you know if you want to see more I have
over 70 recipe videos on my frickin
rawesome recipes playlist linked above
and got a whole bunch of raw recipe
books ranging from super simple hygienic
in 101 frickin awesome recipes in 50
more freaking awesome recipes to more
fancy stuff and Thierry Retreat treats
and American classics that I co-authored
with dr. Douglas Graham swell is
freaking awesome pizza vs check that out
naturally raw some dressings naturally
draw some sauces a whole bunch more
check it all out at my website let me
know what you guys want to see more of
below and you know check out that
mastering raw food nutrition course as
well if you guys click the link in the
resin if you guys ok wow yeah she's like
you're being too shameless babe click
the link below to get a whole bunch more
info in the written post plus that bonus
chilli powder recipe hope you guys loved
this hit subscribe hit like and as
always wishing you much peace lovin see
is no fruit wears is creamy curry is
cocoa butter veggies give 100 foo ooh
don't forget to check out my Ross and
recipes playlist and top left this video
just for you in the top right subscribe
for more on the bottom right and get
your 3 free ebooks in the bottom left
grab my free iPhone app comes a 50 free
recipes common fruit vegetable carry
breakdown food combining chart shopping
cart function and much much more